Guide to the Seymour M. Syna Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Seymour M. Syna Papers,
1955-1994
Syna, Seymour M.
17 linear feet in 11 boxes and 6 flat boxes.
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library. New York, NY.
5002871
Biographical Note
Born 1929 in Ellenville NY, he graduated from Bronx High School of Science in 1946. Later he received his BA from University of Arkansas, finally attending Columbia University School of the Arts finishing with his Ed.D. at Columbia University Teacher's College. His adulthood was spent teaching theater in the NYC public school system, including City College, and working as a theater critic for The New York Tribune.
Scope and Content
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into 5 series:
Series I: Correspondence
Series II: Manuscripts
Series III: Play scripts by Others
Series IV: Documents
Series V: Printed
Subjects
Drama--History and criticism.; New York tribune.
Access Restrictions
This collection has no restrictions.
This collection is located off-site. You will need to request this material from the Rare Book and Manuscript Library at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
- Series I: Correspondence
  - Subseries I.1: General
    - General Correspondence (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Subseries I.2: Complaint Letters
    - Complaint Letters for Syna (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Series II: Manuscripts
  - Subseries II.1: Dramaturgy
    - University Dramaturgy Book (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Subseries II.2: Articles by Syna
    - Photocopies of Articles by Sy Syna (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Original drafts of articles by Sy Syna (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Original drafts of articles by Sy Syna (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Subseries II 3: College Materials
    - Bronx Community College materials (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Subseries II.4: Curriculum
    - Course Curriculum (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Subseries II.5: University Notebook
    - Columbia University Notebook (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Subseries II.6: Street Theater
    - Writings on Street Theater (Box 8, Folder 3 and 4)
  - Subseries II.7: Unidentified Notes
    - Unattached Notes (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Subseries II.8: One Acts by Others
    - One Act Plays by various writers (Box 7, Folder 5 - 8)
  - Subseries II.9: Play scripts by Others
    - The People vs. Ranchman by Elisabeth Marton (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Cyrano by Judith Dvorkin based on the play by Rostand as translated by E.W. Dvorkin, ca. 1964 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - The Tempest by William Shakespeare as made into a workbook by Sy Syna, ca. 1964 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Hamlet by William Shakespeare the Living Shakespeare edition, ca. 1964 (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - Subseries II.10: Screenplay
    - Lost and Found by R.F. Barash, ca. 1976 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Series III: Play scripts by Others
  - Britannicus an adaptation for actors by Robert Clayton Casto, ca. 1962 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - One act plays: The Cat Box by Howard Reynolds; Money Can Buy Anything But Success by Lou Antonio, ca. 1962 (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Series IV: Documents
  - Subseries IV.1: Prize Applications
    - Prize Applications (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Subseries IV.2: Artists' Rights
    - Documents Pertaining to Theatrical Rights (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Series V: Printed
  - Subseries V.1: Ephemera
    - Ephemeral Theatrical Publicity (Box 2, Folder 1 - 3)
    - Ephemeral Theatrical Publicity (Box 3, Folder 1 - 3)
    - Ephemeral Theatrical Publicity (Box 4, Folder 1 and 2)
    - Ephemeral Theatrical Publicity (Box 5, Folder 3 - 5)
    - Ephemeral Theatrical Press (Box 6, Folder 2 - 4)
    - Ephemeral Theatrical Publicity (Box 8, Folder 7 and 8)
    - Ephemeral Soap Opera Publicity (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Subseries V.2: Theatrical Publicity
    - Ephemera (Box 11, Folder 1 - 4)
  - Subseries V.3: Newsletters
    - The Passing Show The Newsletter of the Schubert Archive (Box 5, Folder Folder2)
  - Subseries V.4: Drama Critics Associations
    - Materials from drama critics associations (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Subseries V.5: Off Broadway
    - Off Broadway News Releases (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Subseries V.6: Magazines and other Publications
    - The San Francisco Mime Troupe: The First Ten Years by R.G. Davis; Tulane Drama Review A study of the Problems of the European Theatre by Paula De Caro Various ephemeral theatrical brochures The 4th International Student Festival of the Open Theatre (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Kabuki materials including Japanese postcards (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Copies of Applause from the Denver Center for the Performing Arts, ca. 1996 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Subseries V.7: New York Theatre Review
    - Contains Sy Syna's article Street Theatre in America, January 1979 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Contains Sy Syna's article The Many Faces of Off-Off Broadway, September 1979 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Subseries V.8: Newspapers
    - The Other Paper ca. 1980 Chapter One Published by the Greater New York Chapter of Anta ca. 1962 (Box 223)
    - Copies of the newspaper in which Sy Syna made contributions, ca. 1993 (Box 224)
    - Copies of the newspaper in which Sy Syna made contributions, ca. 1993 (Box 225)
    - Copies of the newspaper in which Sy Syna made contributions, ca. 1993 (Box 226)
    - Copies of the newspaper in which Sy Syna made contributions, ca. 1980 (Box 227)
    - Copies of the newspaper in which Sy Syna made contributions, ca. 1980 (Box 228)